{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Pinky is standing in a queue at a ticket counter. Suppose the ratio of the number of persons standing ahead of Pinky to the number of persons standing behind her in the queue is 3:5. If the total number of persons in the queue is less than 300, then the maximum possible number of persons standing ahead of Pinky is",
        "answer": "112"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a village, the ratio of the number of males to females is 5:4. The ratio of the number of literate males to literate females is 2:3. The ratio of the number of illiterate males to illiterate females is 4:3. If 3600 males in the village are literate, then the total number of females in the village is",
        "answer": "5400"
      },
      {
        "question": "Amal buys 110 kg of syrup and 120 kg of juice, syrup being 20% less costly than juice, per kg. He sells 10 kg of syrup at 10% profit and 20 kg of juice at 20% profit. Mixing the remaining juice and syrup, Amal sells the mixture at ₹308.32 per kg and makes an overall profit of 64%. Then, Amal’s cost price for syrup, in rupees per kg, is",
        "answer": "160"
      },
      {
        "question": "The number of ways of distributing 20 identical balloons among 4 children such that each child gets some balloons but no child gets an odd number of balloons, is",
        "answer": "84"
      },
      {
        "question": "Working alone, the times taken by Anu, Tanu, and Manu to complete any job are in the ratio 5:8:10. They accept a job which they can finish in 4 days if they all work together for 8 hours per day. However, Anu and Tanu work together for the first 6 days, working 6 hours 40 minutes per day. Then, the number of hours that Manu will take to complete the remaining job working alone is",
        "answer": "40"
      },
      {
        "question": "Mr. Pinto invests one-fifth of his capital at 6%, one-third at 10%, and the remaining at 1%, each rate being simple interest per annum. Then, the minimum number of years required for the cumulative interest income from these investments to equal or exceed his initial capital is",
        "answer": "25"
      },
      {
        "question": "Regular polygons A and B have number of sides in the ratio 1:2 and interior angles in the ratio 3:4. Then the number of sides of B equals",
        "answer": "10"
      },
      {
        "question": "The number of distinct integer values of x satisfying 4−log2(x) < 0, 3−log4(x) is",
        "answer": "7"
      },
      {
        "question": "The average of a non-decreasing sequence of N numbers a1, a2, …, aN is 300. If a1 is replaced by 6a1, the new average becomes 400. Then, the number of possible values of a1 is",
        "answer": "17"
      },
      {
        "question": "Suppose for all integers x, there are two functions f and g such that f(x)+f(x–1)–1=0 and g(x)=x^2. If f(x^2 – x) = 5, then the value of the sum f(g(5)) + g(f(5)) is",
        "answer": "50"
      },
      {
        "question": "In an examination, there were 75 questions. 3 marks were awarded for each correct answer, 1 mark was deducted for each wrong answer, and 1 mark was awarded for each unattempted question. Rayan scored a total of 97 marks in the examination. If the number of unattempted questions was higher than the number of attempted questions, then the maximum number of correct answers that Rayan could have given in the examination is",
        "answer": "32"
      },
       {
        "question": "The average of 3 digit terms in an AP 38,55,72....is ",
        "answer": "613"
      },{
        "question": "A school has less than 5000 students and if the students are divided equally into teams of either 9 or 10 or 12 or 25 each,exactly 4 are always left out. However ,if they are divided into teams of 11 each, no one is left out. The maximum number of teams of 12 each that can be formed out of the students in thw school is ",
        "answer": "20"
      },
      {
        "question": "Suppose the medians BD and CE of a traingle ABC interect at a point O.If area of traingle ABC is 108 sq.cm,then area of traingle EOD in sq.cm ,is ",
        "answer": "81"
      }
    ]
  }
  